{
    "0": {
        "question" : "Music for small ensemble (2-10) people one player per part, no conductor",
        "answer": "chamber music"
    },
    "1": {
        "question" : "A work with statement of melody followed by a series of transformations often used in the slow movement of sonata cycle",
        "answer": "theme and variations"
    },
    "2": {
        "question" : "A multi-movement work for soloist(s) and orchestra for virtuosity, generally with a sonata form in movement 1",
        "answer": "concerto"
    },
    "3": {
        "question" : "Typically movement 1 of a sonata cycle. Exposition, development, recapitulation.",
        "answer": "sonata form"
    },
    "4": {
        "question" : "A solo passage in concerti, arias, and large orchestral works. Improvisational in style and virtuosic.",
        "answer": "cadenza"
    },
    "5": {
        "question" : "Instrumental piece, most often for piano based on programmatic elements with evocative title. Sometimes grouped into cycles",
        "answer": "character piece"
    },
    "6": {
        "question" : "Musical setting of a German poem for solo voice and piano accompaniment",
        "answer": "Lied"
    },
    "7": {
        "question" : "A song structure with some repetition of music",
        "answer": "modified strophic form"
    },
    "8": {
        "question" : "ABACA or ABACABA, often used in sonata cycles",
        "answer": "rondo form"
    },
    "9": {
        "question" : "A study, solo instrumental work focusing on one or more technical challenges",
        "answer": "etude"
    },
    "10": {
        "question" : "A drama that is sung. Vocal and instrumental music and drama and visual arts and dance.",
        "answer": "opera"
    }, 
    "11": {
        "question" : "beautiful singing, emphazies by purity of tone and lyrical melodies",
        "answer": "bel canto"
    },
    "12": {
        "question" : "The text of an opera, oratorio, or cantata.",
        "answer": "libretto"
    },
    "13": {
        "question" : "speech-like style of singing used to advance plot",
        "answer": "recitative"
    },
    "14": {
        "question" : "A solo song with orchestral accompaniment, highly emotional, virtuosic",
        "answer": "aria"
    },
    "15": {
        "question" : "Wagner's synthesis of music and drama, differentiating from traditional operas",
        "answer": "music drama"
    },
    "16": {
        "question" : "A musical part that plays to represent a character, setting, etc",
        "answer": "Leitmotif"
    },
    "17": {
        "question" : "Total art work combining text, music, and stagecraft",
        "answer": "Gesamtkunstwerk"
    },
    "18": {
        "question" : "Music with extramusical associations and a descriptive title",
        "answer": "program music"
    },
    "19": {
        "question" : "A single movement orchestral work usually in sonata form, separate from the opera or ballet",
        "answer": "concert overture"
    },
    "20": {
        "question" : "French style with blurring of metric pulse, non-traditional scales, and often programmatic",
        "answer": "impressionism in music"
    },
    "21": {
        "question" : "German style with extreme dissonance and irregular rhythmic groupings",
        "answer": "expressionism in music"
    },
    "22": {
        "question" : "A lack of tonal center, no sense of key",
        "answer": "atonality"
    },
    "23": {
        "question" : "Synonymous with 12-tone-music. Parameters (rhythm, pitch, dynamics) organized with specific ordering and manipulated",
        "answer": "serialism"
    },
    "24": {
        "question" : "Composers add randomness to their scores/performances by allowing the performer to choose parameters",
        "answer": "indeterminary"
    },
    "25": {
        "question" : "Repetition of short melodic, rhyhtmic, harmonic patterns with little variation",
        "answer": "minimalism in music"
    },
    "26": {
        "question" : "A return to absolute music and traditional forms",
        "answer": "neo-Classicism"
    },
    "27": {
        "question" : "Real-time markings on score. Visually descriptive and different notation.",
        "answer": "graphic notation"
    },
    "28": {
        "question" : "multi-movement orchestral work, 4 movements, at least one sonata form",
        "answer": "symphony"
    },
    "29": {
        "question" : "Material from one movement appears in another movement for structural unity",
        "answer": "cyclical structure"
    },
    "30": {
        "question" : "scale with 5 different pitches",
        "answer": "pentatonic scale"
    },
    "31": {
        "question" : "scale with 6 different pitches separated by whole step",
        "answer": "whole-tone scale"
    },
    "32": {
        "question" : "The basis of 12-tone compositions. Tone row is manipulated.",
        "answer": "tone row"
    },
    "33": {
        "question" : "Rewriting with intervals flipped",
        "answer": "inversion"
    },
    "34": {
        "question" : "Rewriting melody backwards",
        "answer": "retrograde"
    },
    "35": {
        "question" : "Based on order of 12 chromatic pitches to organize atonal music",
        "answer": "12-tone music"
    },
    "36": {
        "question" : "Trio of Arnold Schoenberg, Anton Webern, Alban Berg who developed 12-tone music",
        "answer": "Second Viennese School"
    },
    "37": {
        "question" : "A chord made of major and minor seconds",
        "answer": "cluster chord"
    },
    "38": {
        "question" : "Simultaneously using more than one key",
        "answer": "polytonality"
    },
    "39": {
        "question" : "The art of designing dance steps/movements",
        "answer": "choreography"
    },
    "40": {
        "question" : "Highly stylized type of dance that interprets a story",
        "answer": "ballet"
    },
    "41": {
        "question" : "A group of orchestral movements from larger dramatic works played in a concert setting",
        "answer": "orchestral suite"
    },
    "42": {
        "question" : "Any scale that can only be transposed once",
        "answer": "mode of limited transposition"
    },
    "43": {
        "question" : "Many separate melodic strands weaved together",
        "answer": "micropolyphony"
    },
    "44": {
        "question" : "Produced on a string instrument by depressing at specific points",
        "answer": "harmonics"
    },
    "45": {
        "question" : "A loud ceremonial piece played on important occasions",
        "answer": "fanfare"
    },
    "46": {
        "question" : "Inserting objects in between strings to make different sounds",
        "answer": "prepared piano"
    }
}